A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Arthur Massolo, Series 19 FA364
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial records, Arthur Massolo, Series 19
1966-1971
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
Massolo, Arthur
FA364
1.14 Cubic Feet
Biographical/Historical note
Nelson A. Rockefeller served as governor of New York from January 1, 1959, to December 18, 1973. He was the first person elected to four consecutive four-year terms as a state governor.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement note
This is a partial alphabetical run of corrrespondence, organized by last name (K-S only).
Scope and Contents note
NOTE TO RESEARCHERS
This series contains the office files of Arthur Massolo. They document official activities in the execution of his duties as a member of Nelson A. Rockefeller's staff. The actions, decisions, and exchanges of information or points of view documented here occurred in the course of proposing and implementing policies for the Rockefeller administration, political campaigns, and/or Rockefeller's personal activities. However, unless a document is personally signed by Nelson A. Rockefeller, or is referred to in a document personally signed by him, it should not be assumed he saw the document or was aware of its existence or substance. Furthermore, researchers should bear in mind that staff files may contain documents or drafts addressed to Rockefeller that were never shown to him.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
This series contains a portion of the office files of Arthur Massolo, who served in the Appointments Office during Nelson A. Rockefeller's third gubernatorial term. This incomplete selection of papers is composed entirely of correspondence with individuals seeking employment in the Rockefeller administration. As Assistant Appointments Officer to the Governor, Massolo forwarded the correspondence to the appropriate department. Massolo often included cover memoranda with recommendations on the individuals to the directors, commissioners, or secretaries of the many New York State departments.
There is no indication as to why those individuals who have their own folders were given such a distinction. Arthur J. Lewis wrote several letters to Massolo seeking state aid on behalf of his disabled son. Rose Shapiro was appointed as Governor Rockefeller's new assistant for narcotics in February 1970. Folder 12, Puerto Ricans Meeting, March 22, 1967, contains Massolo's notes from this meeting.
Other Finding Aids note
Detailed finding aids for each series of this collection are available:
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Appointments Office (FA353)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Assembly and Senate Memos (FA354)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Joseph H. Boyd (FA355)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, James Cannon (FA356)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Affirmative Action (N. Lee Cook) (FA357)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Counsel's Office (FA358)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York State Committee to Reelect the President (FA359)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Jerry A. Danzig (FA360)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Executive Chamber (FA361)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, 55th Street (FA362)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Issue Books (FA363)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Hugh Morrow (FA242)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Office (FA365)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Civil Service Resolutions (Charles H. Palmer) (FA366)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Political Files (FA367)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Press Office (FA368)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Public Relations (FA369)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Departmental Reports (FA370)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, William J. Ronan (FA371)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Speeches (FA372)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Diane Van Wie (FA373)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Ann C. Whitman, Gubernatorial (FA374)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Gene Wyckoff (FA375)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Republican State Fund Raising Reports (FA376)
Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1962; Federal government -- United States; Government policy; Civil service -- New York (State); Economics; Civil defense -- United States; Civil service; Arms control -- United States; Civil defense; Affirmative action programs -- New York (State); Arms control; Human rights; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1970; International relations; International economic relations; International relations -- United States; Latin America; Legislation -- New York (State); New York (N.Y.); New York (State); Political campaigns -- United States; Political science; Presidential campaigns -- United States; United States; State governments -- United States; Vice-Presidents -- United States; Presidential candidates -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1966; Public relations; Public policy
- State Issues
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence with individuals seeking employment in the Rockefeller administration; memoranda with New York State departments on possible candidates for position.
  - K, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - K, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - L, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - L, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Lewis, Arthur L., 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - M, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - M, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mc, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - N, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - O, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - P, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Puerto Ricans, Meeting, March 22, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Q, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - R, 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - R, 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - S, 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - S, 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - S, 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Shapiro, Rose, 1966-1971 (Box 3, Folder 19)